<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Blogs on Rust AV</title><link>https://rustav.org/blog/</link><description>Recent content in Blogs on Rust AV</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 25 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://rustav.org/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Implementing Tile Encoding in rav1e</title><link>https://rustav.org/blog/2019-04-25-implementing-tile-encoding-in-rav1e./</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rustav.org/blog/2019-04-25-implementing-tile-encoding-in-rav1e./</guid><description>During the last few months at Videolabs, I added support for tile encoding in rav1e.
What is this? AV1 is an open and royalty-free video coding format, concurrent with HEVC.
Rav1e is an encoder written in Rust, developped by Mozilla/Xiph. As such, it takes an input video and encodes it to produce a valid AV1 bitstream.
Tile encoding Tile encoding consists in splitting video frames into tiles that can be encoded and decoded independently in parallel (to use several CPUs), at the cost of a small loss in compression efficiency.</description></item><item><title>Using rav1e - from your own code</title><link>https://rustav.org/blog/2019-04-09-using-rav1e-from-your-code/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rustav.org/blog/2019-04-09-using-rav1e-from-your-code/</guid><description>AV1, Rav1e, Crav1e, an intro AV1 is a modern video codec brought to you by an alliance of many different bigger and smaller players in the multimedia field. I&amp;rsquo;m part of the VideoLAN organization and I spent quite a bit of time on this codec lately.
rav1e: The safest and fastest AV1 encoder, built by many volunteers and Mozilla/Xiph developers. It is written in rust and strives to provide good speed, quality and stay maintainable.</description></item><item><title>Why you should care about AOM Analyzer</title><link>https://rustav.org/blog/2019-02-18-why-you-should-care-about-aom-analyzer-tool-e2808b/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rustav.org/blog/2019-02-18-why-you-should-care-about-aom-analyzer-tool-e2808b/</guid><description>Hi Folks,
It&amp;rsquo;s been a while I have written a blog, this is the right time I guess. So lately I am trying to do a kind of research with video encoding in power constrained devices as part of my undergrad thesis project. So I was going into more details about encoders in general. After that, I have also gone through the details about HEVC, AV1 and all.
We all know about very positive development advances in AV1 when we see with HEVC.</description></item></channel></rss>