<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blogs on rav1e</title>
    <link>https://rav1e.rs/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blogs on rav1e</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 19 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://rav1e.rs/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>A great 2018, an even better 2019</title>
      <link>https://rav1e.rs/blog/2018-12-recap-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rav1e.rs/blog/2018-12-recap-2018/</guid>
      <description>A year ago, Tokio was a very different library. It includes the (now deprecated) tokio-core which provided a future executor, I/O selector, and basic TCP/UDP types in a single library. It also included tokio-proto, but we won&amp;rsquo;t talk about that. Over the past year, Tokio has grown to become Rust&amp;rsquo;s asynchronous I/O platform. It has been adopted by a number of large companies to build apps.
A lot was achieved in 2018.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing the Tokio Doc Push (we need you!)</title>
      <link>https://rav1e.rs/blog/2018-10-doc-blitz/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rav1e.rs/blog/2018-10-doc-blitz/</guid>
      <description>In the past, there has been reoccurring feedback that Tokio is hard to understand. I believe a lack of good documentation plays a significant part. It&amp;rsquo;s time to fix this problem.
And because Tokio is open source, it is on us (the community) to make this happen! 👏
But don&amp;rsquo;t worry, this isn&amp;rsquo;t an aimless request to contribute documentation. It does, however, require participation. There are ways to get involved at any level of prior Tokio experience.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Experimental async / await support for Tokio</title>
      <link>https://rav1e.rs/blog/2018-08-async-await/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rav1e.rs/blog/2018-08-async-await/</guid>
      <description>Happy Monday!
In case you haven&amp;rsquo;t heard, async / await is a big new feature that is being worked on for Rust. It aims to make asynchronous programming easy (well, at least a little bit easier than it is today). The work has been on going for a while and is already usable today on the Rust nightly channel.
I&amp;rsquo;m happy to announce that Tokio now has experimental async / await support!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tokio 0.1.8 with many incremental improvements</title>
      <link>https://rav1e.rs/blog/2018-08-incremental-improvements/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rav1e.rs/blog/2018-08-incremental-improvements/</guid>
      <description>It took a bit longer than I had initially hoped (as it always does), but a new Tokio version has been released. This release includes, among other features, a new set of APIs that allow performing filesystem operations from an asynchronous context, concurrency improvements, timer improvements, and more (including bug fixes, so be sure to update!).
It has been a little bit since the last post. There haven&amp;rsquo;t been any big feature releases, but that doesn&amp;rsquo;t mean that we have been idle.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Tokio release, now with filesystem support</title>
      <link>https://rav1e.rs/blog/2018-05-tokio-fs/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rav1e.rs/blog/2018-05-tokio-fs/</guid>
      <description>It took a bit longer than I had initially hoped (as it always does), but a new Tokio version has been released. This release includes, among other features, a new set of APIs that allow performing filesystem operations from an asynchronous context.
Filesystem APIs Interacting with files (and other filesystem types) requires* blocking system calls and we all know that blocking and asynchronous do not mix. So, historically, when people ask &amp;ldquo;how do I read from and write to files?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Timer implementation</title>
      <link>https://rav1e.rs/blog/2018-03-timers/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rav1e.rs/blog/2018-03-timers/</guid>
      <description>Happy Friday all!
To close out a great week, there is a new release of Tokio. This release includes a brand new timer implementation.
Timers Sometimes (often), one wants to execute code in relation to time. Maybe a function needs to run at a specific instant. Maybe a read needs to be limited to a fixed duration. For working with time, one needs access to a timer!
Some history The tokio-timer crate has been around for a while.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing the Tokio runtime</title>
      <link>https://rav1e.rs/blog/2018-03-tokio-runtime/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rav1e.rs/blog/2018-03-tokio-runtime/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m happy to announce a new release of Tokio. This release includes the first iteration of the Tokio Runtime.
tl;dr This is how a multi-threaded Tokio based server is now written:
extern crate tokio; use tokio::net::TcpListener; use tokio::prelude::*; fn process(s: TcpStream) -&amp;gt; impl Future&amp;lt;Item = (), Error = ()&amp;gt; + Send { ... } let addr = &amp;quot;127.0.0.1:8080&amp;quot;.parse().unwrap(); let listener = TcpListener::bind(&amp;amp;addr).unwrap(); let server = listener.incoming() .map_err(|e| println!(&amp;quot;error = {:?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tokio Reform is Shipped and the Road to 0.2</title>
      <link>https://rav1e.rs/blog/2018-02-tokio-reform-shipped/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rav1e.rs/blog/2018-02-tokio-reform-shipped/</guid>
      <description>Hi all!
I&amp;rsquo;m happy to announce that today, the changes proposed in the reform RFC have been released to crates.io as tokio 0.1.
The primary changes are:
 Add a default global event loop, eliminating the need for setting up and managing your own event loop in the vast majority of cases.
 Decouple all task execution functionality from Tokio.
  The new global event loop Up until today, creating an event loop was a manual process.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An RFC for a Tokio revamp</title>
      <link>https://rav1e.rs/blog/2017-09-tokio-reform/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rav1e.rs/blog/2017-09-tokio-reform/</guid>
      <description>Hi there, Tokio community!
Carl, Alex, and myself have been hard at work developing ways to simplify, streamline, and focus the Tokio project. As part of this effort, we have written the first-ever Tokio RFC!
Here&amp;rsquo;s a quick run-down of what&amp;rsquo;s being proposed.
 Add a global event loop in tokio-core that is managed automatically by default. This change eliminates the need for setting up and managing your own event loop in the vast majority of cases.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing the tokio-io Crate</title>
      <link>https://rav1e.rs/blog/2017-03-tokio-io/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rav1e.rs/blog/2017-03-tokio-io/</guid>
      <description>Today we&amp;rsquo;re happy to announce a new crate and several new tools to work with in the Tokio stack. This represents the culmination of a number of parallel updates to various bits and pieces, they just happened to conveniently land all around the same time! In a nutshell the improvements are:
 A new tokio-io crate extracted from tokio-core, deprecating the tokio_core::io module. Introduction of the bytes crate to tokio-io allowing abstraction over buffering and leveraging underlying functionality like vectored I/O.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing Tokio 0.1</title>
      <link>https://rav1e.rs/blog/2017-01-tokio-0-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rav1e.rs/blog/2017-01-tokio-0-1/</guid>
      <description>Today we are publishing the preliminary version of the Tokio stack, 0.1!
Tokio is a platform for writing fast networking code in Rust. It&amp;rsquo;s built on futures, a zero-cost abstraction for asynchronous programming in Rust. It provides a suite of basic tools, tokio-core, for asynchronous I/O with futures. It also provides a higher-level layer, tokio-proto, for easily building sophisticated servers and clients; all you have to do is handle message serialization.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>